[
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is not part of the 4 gospels in New Testament",
        "option": [
            "John",
            "Mattew",
            "Mark",
            "Luke",
            "Matthew"
        ],
        "answer": "Mattew",
        "hint": "Spelling is important!",
        "explanation": "The correct spelling is Matthew not Mattew"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many 'books' are there in the protestant's Bible?",
        "option": [
            "73",
            "66",
            "39",
            "27",
            "None of the Above"
        ],
        "answer": "66",
        "hint": "There is new and old testament but we don't include apocryphal books",
        "explanation": "There is a total of 39 in OT, 27 in new testament which is total of 66 books"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does NKJV stands for?",
        "option": [
            "Noble King James Version",
            "Nice King Jesus Version",
            "Notorious Knight Joe Version",
            "New Junior Kindergartener Version",
            "New King James Version"
        ],
        "answer": "New King James Version",
        "hint": "It is a version of bible",
        "explanation": "New King James Version is the correct version, the rest should not exist!"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is swallowed by a great fish so that he would go to Nineveh?",
        "option": [
            "Jonah",
            "Joseph",
            "Joshua",
            "Peter",
            "Moses"
        ],
        "answer": "Jonah",
        "hint": "His name is one of the book in the bible!",
        "explanation": "Jonah in the book of 'Jonah' is being swallowed by a great fish(or Leviathan)!"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which bible books has the most number of chapters?",
        "option": [
            "Jonah",
            "Revelation",
            "Joshua",
            "Psalms",
            "Isaiah"
        ],
        "answer": "Psalms",
        "hint": "There is 150 chapters in this book!",
        "explanation": "Psalms is the book with the most number of chapters."
    },
    {
        "question": "How did Enoch die?",
        "option": [
            "Flood",
            "Raining of fire and brimstone",
            "Murdered",
            "Struck dead by God",
            "None of the Above"
        ],
        "answer": "None of the Above",
        "hint": "Genesis 5:24!",
        "explanation": "Genesis 5:24 \nAnd Enoch walked with God; and he was not, for God took him."
    },
    {
        "question": "How many children does Jacob has?",
        "option": [
            "2",
            "7",
            "11",
            "12",
            "13"
        ],
        "answer": "13",
        "hint": "Remember to include both sons and daughters",
        "explanation": "Jacob has 12 sons and 1 daughter named Dinah"
    },
    {
        "question": "There are 12 tribes of Israel, which does Jesus belongs to?",
        "option": [
            "Joseph",
            "Levi",
            "Judah",
            "Issachar",
            "Gad"
        ],
        "answer": "Judah",
        "hint": "Jesus is also known as the lion of ___?",
        "explanation": "Matthew 1:2 \nBased on Jesus genealogy, he is a descendant of Judah"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who betrayed Jesus?",
        "option": [
            "Peter",
            "Pilate",
            "Mary",
            "Judas",
            "Lazarus"
        ],
        "answer": "Judas",
        "hint": "He is one of the 12 apostles that Jesus appointed",
        "explanation": "Luke 27:47-48 \nJudas betrayed Jesus with a kiss"
    },
    {
        "question": "The scribes and Pharisees bring a woman caught in adultery to Jesus and asked him about stoning her. Who was the first one to cast the stone?",
        "option": [
            "Chief priest",
            "One of the scribes",
            "One of the Pharisees",
            "Jesus",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "None of the above",
        "hint": "He is who is without sin among you, let him throw a stone at her first",
        "explanation": "John 8:7-11 \nAfter hearing what Jesus said they went out one by one"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many times Peter denies Jesus before the rooster crowed?",
        "option": [
            "None, he fell asleep because he is too tired",
            "1",
            "2",
            "3",
            "Countless, as he is being asked too many times"
        ],
        "answer": "3",
        "hint": "Jesus told him that",
        "explanation": "luke 22:34 \nThen He said, 'I tell you, Peter, the rooster shall not crow this day before you will deny three times that you know Me.'"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is not one of the seven feast of the Lord?",
        "option": [
            "Unleavened Bread",
            "First fruits",
            "Aged Wine",
            "Trumpets",
            "Atonement"
        ],
        "answer": "Aged Wine",
        "hint": "The answer might sounds right but it isn't",
        "explanation": "The 7 feasts are Passover, Unleavened Bread, First Fruits, Shavuot, Trumpets, Atonement, Tabernacles"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the parable of good samaritan (Luke10:25-35), who helped the wounded man?",
        "option": [
            "A Priest",
            "His father",
            "Levite",
            "A Samaritan",
            "The Thieves"
        ],
        "answer": "A Samaritan",
        "hint": "What is this parable called?",
        "explanation": "Luke 10:33 \nBut a certain Samaritan, as he journeyed, came where he was. And when he saw him, he had compassion."
    },
    {
        "question": "When John the Baptist preach in the wilderness of Judea, he ate ___ and honey?",
        "option": [
            "Crickets",
            "Dates",
            "Milk",
            "Locusts",
            "Fruits"
        ],
        "answer": "Locusts",
        "hint": "Not something most people will want to eat",
        "explanation": "Matthew 3:4 \nNow John himself was clothed in camel's hair, with a leather belt around his waist; and his food was locusts and wild honey."
    },
    {
        "question": "How many stones did David bring to take down Goliath?",
        "option": [
            "1",
            "3",
            "5",
            "7",
            "12"
        ],
        "answer": "5",
        "hint": "The question stated 'bring' not 'kill'",
        "explanation": "1Sam 17:40 \nThen he took his staff in his hand; and he chose for himself five smooth stones from the brook..."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Lord rained brimstone and fire on Sodom and Gomorrah. Lot's wife looked back and became ___?",
        "option": [
            "Statue of Liberty",
            "Roasted Meat",
            "Puddle of water",
            "A Lump of Coal",
            "A pillar of salt"
        ],
        "answer": "A pillar of salt",
        "hint": "It is probably still standing",
        "explanation": "Gen 19:26 \nBut his wife looked back behind him, and she became a pillar of salt."
    },
    {
        "question": "Fill in the blank. For God so loved the world that He gave His only begotten Son, ______",
        "option": [
            "that the world through Him might be saved.",
            "that whoever believes in Him should not perish but have everlasting life.",
            "that he who does not believe the Son shall not see life.",
            "so he can see the kingdom of God.",
            "that the light has come into the world."
        ],
        "answer": "that whoever believes in Him should not perish but have everlasting life.",
        "hint": "Something to do with life",
        "explanation": "John 3:16 \nFor God so loved the world that He gave His only begotten Son, that whoever believes in Him should not perish but have everlasting life."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Jacob's new name?",
        "option": [
            "Adam",
            "Gideon",
            "Issac",
            "Israel",
            "Joseph"
        ],
        "answer": "Israel",
        "hint": "It is a name of a country today!",
        "explanation": "Gen 32:28 \nAnd He said, â€œYour name shall no longer be called Jacob, but Israel; ..."
    },
    {
        "question": "What did Jesus sat on when he enter into Jerusalem?",
        "option": [
            "Human",
            "Horse",
            "Colt",
            "Lion",
            "Porcupine"
        ],
        "answer": "Colt",
        "hint": "It is unexpected but not ridiculous!",
        "explanation": "Mark 11:7 \nThen they brought the colt to Jesus and threw their clothes on it, and He sat on it."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is not a book in the bible?",
        "option": [
            "3 Peter",
            "Romans",
            "Acts",
            "Amos",
            "2 John"
        ],
        "answer": "3 Peter",
        "hint": "The number seems fishy!",
        "explanation": "There is only 1,2 Peter, but there is 1, 2, 3 John!"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the parable of the wise and foolish virgins, what did the follish virgins lacked of?",
        "option": [
            "Candle",
            "Lighter",
            "Matchsticks",
            "Oil",
            "Lamp"
        ],
        "answer": "Oil",
        "hint": "Some of these items don't exist in ancient times!",
        "explanation": "Mat 25:3 \nThose who were foolish took their lamps and took no oil with them,"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these characters get to lived an additional 15 years?",
        "option": [
            "Moses",
            "Joshua",
            "Peter",
            "Hezekiah",
            "James"
        ],
        "answer": "Hezekiah",
        "hint": "He is a king from the old testament",
        "explanation": "2 Kings 20:6 \nAnd I will add to your days fifteen years. ..."
    },
    {
        "question": "How long did it rain when Noah was on the ark?",
        "option": [
            "Forty years",
            "Seven days and seven nights",
            "Forty days and forty nights",
            "Seven years",
            "Three days and three nights"
        ],
        "answer": "Forty days and forty nights",
        "hint": "It is long but not that long",
        "explanation": "Gen 7:12 \nAnd the rain was on the earth forty days and forty nights."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which tribe has no part nor inheritance with Israel?",
        "option": [
            "Tribe of Levi",
            "Tribe of Reuben",
            "Tribe of Judah",
            "Tribe of Manasseh",
            "Tribe of Simeon"
        ],
        "answer": "Tribe of Levi",
        "hint": "They are also known as priests!",
        "explanation": "Deut 18:1 \nThe priests, the Levitesâ€”all the tribe of Leviâ€”shall have [a]no part nor inheritance with Israel ..."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of this is not a fruit of the Spirit mentioned in Galatian 5s?",
        "option": [
            "Love",
            "Peace",
            "Faithfulness",
            "Gentleness",
            "Passion Fruit"
        ],
        "answer": "Passion Fruit",
        "hint": "Mmmm sweet and sour!",
        "explanation": "Gal 5:22-23 \nBut the fruit of the Spirit is love, joy, peace, longsuffering, kindness, goodness, faithfulness, gentleness, self-control ..."
    }
]